Please insert coins.
Whoa!
Check it out!
Look at all that juicy ocean water!
That's Director Scorching.
He's the epitome of extra.
How does she lug this around
without throwing out her back?
That's child's play for someone
with the blessing of weight.
What even is that?
Basically, it means she can alter
the weight of anything she touches.
She can make stuff lighter or
heavier whenever she wants.
Makes hauling junk a breeze.
So I take it you refused
Captain Carriol's invitation
and disappeared into the
ocean to get away from him?
That's correct, but it's lame.
I was hunkered down on a
nice island. Till that...
Is there some special
reason you were hunkered?
I was waiting for him
to return to my side.
Who's the guy?
Don't tell me it's that
bastard who left you!
Some clams never learn.
Don't say that.
It's not true.
I know in my heart
he'll come back one day.
He will.
He'll return to pity.
I've got to be patient.
That's all there is to it!
Clinging to the memory of a man
who abandoned her without remorse,
she's deluded herself into believing
they'll see each other again.
But it's just a fantasy.
Also, that loser was a
bonafide marriage fraudster.
But she refuses to believe us no matter
how many times we try to tell her.
Oh, I've seen her.
When the captain came
to invite me, I'm sure.
That's Sulrin, a snow spirit like Kikoyu
whose allegiance lies with the Netherlord.
The snowstorms she conjures
are no laughing matter.
We're gonna have our work cut out for
us without Kikoyu around to back us up.
No joke.
That's exactly why Director Bear sent
someone along to aid the mission.
It's been a dog's age since I've
been to the Dog Mountain Stratum,
but it doesn't hold a candle
to the scorching sand.
Let's be real, it's
lukewarm and best out here!
I'm starting to think this was
some cruel prank, care of the bear.
Meekaboo, are you getting
enough nutrition in that thing?
Some food would cheer you up.
Somebody help me!
Whoa, a living drum kit!
This guy's the life of the party!
You can give me a kid if you don't!
Those two are about as
compatible as fire and water.
Here we
go.
Oh
That's it.
I want to go home.
It's scary out there.
He poured fuel on the flame
of her shut-in tendencies.
Time to step in.
Hello, Pity.
It's Pity.
What's up?
You went, sir-um-sir-what-eeks.
So, um, that was good.
Thanks a lot
You too?
Sir, thank you very much
What a peculiar magic item.
You're a real person, I can already tell.
Who would have thunk a
clam in a vending machine
would get along so well
and yet here we are?
I'm just glad I managed
to cheer her up a little.
I'm a nuisance.
I cause trouble for everyone around me.
And that especially goes for him.
I know he's a liar, but I still
can't bring myself to let go.
I'm so self-centered, aren't I?
A truly terrible person.
Well, it could be you earned
for instance if you went.
Thing is, I'm only good at defense.
You think they'd want
someone like me around? Yes.
I'm the evil evil.
You believe in me?
Well then, maybe I'll
try just a bit harder.
The clam is emerging from her shell.
Oh, you gotta come taste
that salty sea air with me.
Not sure that's going to
help her want to open up,
but that combo is a
pretty darn good start.
Over there that's my
island it's still too far
away to really see
anything we can do better
than that form change tourist destinations
often have binocular
rentals i know they're
not packaged goods but i've been able to
change into service
machines since reaching rank
two i could wax poetic about the different
types but we're short
on time so i'll refrain
wow everything's crystal clear
Isn't that...
Pretty sure I see the fool's boat.
I'm back.
Hey, I was starting to worry about you?
What's with the makeshift entourage?
Heavy cast an illusion on us
to protect our identities.
Now we're total strangers
and an adorable kitty.
Oh, right.
The sea monsters, they've
been causing trouble.
So I hired bodyguards. Good thinking.
You need all the offensive
help you can get.
Come on.
Join our party, Pity.
It's going at a snail's pace.
Conquering the dungeon would be
a breeze with you on defense.
I'm waiting for him to come back.
So I can't go?
Well, we only ask that
you give it some thought.
Once this dungeon is handled,
we'll do what we can to help you.
We'll even help you track
down your long-lost lover.
Are you in?
Sorry. Still a no.
I can't go with you. I refuse.
Had a feeling you'd say that.
Way too bad.
We'd better step outside.
I'd hate to wreck your little house
by starting a nasty brawl here.
I breach.
Really?
Boxxo?
What do you know?
Seems the gang's all here.
Say, how about we indulge in some booze
while we work through our differences?
I wouldn't mind some of Bokso's finest.
We miss his deep-fried meats and
delightfully fizzy drinks so much it hurts.
Don't we, Shiro?
Just thinking about it
makes me hungry and thirsty.
It feels like it's been
forever, doesn't it?
Don't you dare look at me
with those wistful eyes.
In case you've forgotten,
we're enemies at the Mo.
It's too late.
They're clearly jonesing to fight. I know.
La-I-X-R-E-T.
Yeah.
We surveyed a hundred people
in the Clearflow Lake Stratum
and asked what they think of
Captain Carriol's actions.
Lamas and I collected a
few choice opinions about
the Menagerie of Fools
for just such an occasion.
First question.
What do you think of them working for the
Netherlord in order to
help a child in need?
They had three options
they could choose from.
Forgivable, unforgivable, and undecided.
Twelve people said forgivable.
Sixty said unforgivable.
And twenty-eight said undecided.
That's not nearly as
bad as I was expecting.
The people who said forgivable
had something in common.
They all said things like,
it's possible I would do the same thing
if I thought it would help my child.
Or, as a parent, I can't judge
without knowing the details.
Sounds tragic. Next question.
Do you think Filmina both deserves and
could do a lot better than Captain Carioid?
Hold on a sec.
There's no reason to
read that one out loud.
Don't judge stuff when she's
getting in the good stuff.
You're gonna have to hold him tighter.
62 said definitely.
16 said perfect mismatch.
And 22 said hope he dies. That's rude.
What are those the choices anyway?
Everyone seems to be in agreement.
Interesting.
Perhaps I should have searched longer
to find a more suitable husband.
Now for the final question.
If they ever came back and
apologized and accepted punishment,
would you forgive them?
The moment of truth has arrived.
It's the whole reason we went polling.
Twenty said I couldn't.
And eighty said I'd forgive them.
That result isn't all that
surprising when you think about it.
This whole time, they've been
focused on clearing the lowest floor,
so they haven't directly hurt anyone.
Besides, the folks in the Clear Flow
Lake Stratum are kind and open-minded.
I mean, seriously, they learned to embrace
a freaking talking vending machine.
I'll give you a sample of what they said.
They should have known that we would have
had their backs if they were in trouble.
If they weren't so stupid, we
could have pitched in to help.
There's more!
Just come back already.
Pay for the booze and we'll let it go.
It's the most natural thing in the world
for a parent to want to protect their kid.
But it's important to remember that
every action has a ripple effect.
Is this what your child
would want for you?
I'd be happy to knock some sense
into those empty heads of theirs.
So tell those whippersnappers
to hurry back!
If I had to guess, I'd say those
last two are Yumite and Shimelai.
Knowing them,
I bet they're filled with
regret for not realizing
how much the captain and
his wife were suffering.
Figures.
Should've known.
They're all busy-bodied.
Oh, and here's one for
you from Miss Shirley.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
I think we've heard
enough for today, Lamas.
No need to read that one.
Captain, you've got a record-setting
tab, so please come and pay it.
The young ladies of our fine establishment
miss your company, as well as that of Mr.
Akka and Mr.
Shiro.
So, don't keep us waiting. XOXO!
Care to explain yourself?
You can tell what it sounds like.
The boys were curious about the place.
They practically dragged me, kicking and
screaming, so they could have a peek.
I didn't really have a
choice in the matter.
Tell her the truth, Dad.
You're the one who made us promise
not to tell Mom about our field trip.
It was your idea, and you kept
bragging about how you're a regular.
I'm sure your drinks were more enjoyable
with pretty ladies by your side.
I bet you had the time of
your life there, didn't you?
I should probably intervene
before things get violent.
Well, it's pretty obvious
who's behind this attack.
Weird.
She's not alone.
Have you finished blabbing
about your feelings?
I certainly hope you're not
considering betraying the Netherlord.
Of course not.
I wouldn't dream of it.
The debt we owe is too steep for that.
It's been a blast, but the reunion's over.
What does he mean he owes
the Netherlord a debt?
I'd love to stay and chat
about the good old days.
If we had crossed paths sooner, things
may have turned out differently.
It's too late.
We've gone past the point of no return.
I'm truly sorry.
Yeah, me too. Really.
That's how it goes.
What are you even talking about?
I'm sure we can find a
way to save your son,
even without asking the
stupid Netherlord to help out!
You're so naive it's amusing you think
they're still worried about saving their son.
I'm happy to report that's not
a concern of theirs anymore.
What are you saying it's time
for show and tell it can't be.
That's the captain's son.
Boxo boxo boxo i'm taking excellent
care of his darling little boy.
so there's no longer any
need to remove the curse.
I have taken it upon myself to
relieve this sweet child of his pain.
Since when can you remove curses?
Is that a snow spirit thing?
Beheading a snow spirit who
has blossomed into adulthood
transforms them into a statue
that can remove curses.
But what do you suppose happens if one
manages to keep her head on her shoulders?
The ability to remove curses is a
talent that is inherent to my kind.
As we mature, our abilities
continue to grow along with us.
The only catch is that the
target must remain near.
If you attempt to pry this child from my
grasp, his excruciating pain will return.
So basically you're holding a kid hostage.
This boy isn't a hostage.
I'm saving the captain's precious
son from a wretched existence.
This family wishes to satisfy my
every whim as a show of gratitude.
She's exactly right.
So I'm afraid we have no
choice but to serve the
Netherlord and fight to clear
the dungeon on his behalf.
You've made your choice, and nothing
we say could make you change your mind.
Unfortunately, the only option
left to us is to use force.
You're just another sad Netherlord crony.
Don't expect a shred of mercy.
Love makes fools of all of us.
But hurting others, even for
love, that's just despicable.
I can't help but notice
your short one-snow spirit,
meaning none of you are
capable of stopping me.
from turning everyone
standing here to ice.
Not so fast.
This is kind of personal,
so why not let us handle it?
Don't be such a fool.
Unless you mean to defy me.
That's enough!
How can you be so cruel?
That was stupid! I'm sorry!
Let's just make it stop!
Better than I think it's
about time we end this farce.
I'm going to kill every
last one of you. How rude!
We'd better split up so she can't
hit us all at the same time.
I've had enough to hear
with your dirty tricks!
If the people fighting aren't getting
fired up, it's not a real battle!
Are you an actual imbecile?
You thought it was a good idea to charge
a snow spirit without any forethought?
That was barely looked warm.
Snow spirits are lame.
You're all cold as ice and boring to boot.
I would have assumed your
race already died off.
You're a true annoyance.
A flame spirit.
How come no one gave us the heads-up,
Director Scorching's a flame spirit?
Did you know, Hewleby? I did.
I also know their powers are essentially
the opposite of the snow spirits.
As you might have guessed?
They can control fire
and can be a bit hot.
A Snow Spirit's natural enemy.
Their people have fought countless wars.
That explains why Director
Vare chose him for the job.
It's brilliant!
With flame powers, he can go
toe-to-toe with Soul Ream!
Hmph.
Ice Queen's mine, so sit
back and enjoy the show.
This measly battleground's
not gonna cut it!
Guess there's no use to
laying the inevitable captain.
This time will be different than the last.
I'm dead serious about
walking away the victor.
Things are about to get interesting.
I request to be the one to do it.
Quite the compliment.
Then I'll focus on the vice captain.
I'll beat up his stupid Osprey.
I'm not stupid, you loudmouthed loser!
Yeah, loser!
Children, it seems the time has
come to reveal our true forms.
She has wings?
The vice-captain has vamp fiend
blood flowing through her veins.
Aw, that's kinda badass, though.
Gotta say, with those wings, she looks
more like a fallen angel than a vampire!
Shall we let the battle begin?
Let's go!
So Filmina exploded.
So what am I supposed to do now?
You didn't explode anyone.
She conjured a water double to trick you.
The real her is there.
That was a noble effort.
Your bemusing attacks are
You're absolutely fearsome.
Too bad for you, I can simply fly away.
Good thinking!
We didn't used to have a way to fight
airborne enemies, but that was then.
Boom!
Check out this transformation!
The coin locker!
It's OWN!
I went ahead and blocked these bottled
beauties from entering my barrier.
You forgot I can control water!
Yeah, that's not ordinary water.
I know I've felt this
slimy texture before.
It was back in the origin straddle.
You bet you have.
It's a lubricant, gently-scented
lotion. Oh, no. My wings.
That was good.
But I'm afraid you're still
no match for my water.
Whoa!
Nice!
That went surprisingly well.
Ah!
She's killing it!
Why must you attack poor Pity?
I get it.
The woman who stole my
man put you up to this.
Pity won't give in.
The battle just started and she's
already come up with her own head cannon.
Need backup?
That's scary.
It's starting to look like
we'll have to buy some
time until Dad or Sulream
can come and bail us out.
Well said.
Let's go.
We can't defeat them if they run away.
Good thing I'm a vending machine.
I came prepared for anything.
How inspired.
I think I know what you're planning.
Lock it. Charge. Right.
Special delivery.
Not our best moment.
You can't defeat us with
a bevy of busty ladies.
Yeah...
How dare you! That's cheating!
Boxxo, that was gross.
Why am I the one who's in hot water?
Those eyes of yours,
they're quite troublesome.
Colour me impressed.
Guess I'm not getting
anything by you, am I?
If I'm reading the room correctly,
it seems his eye breach ability
does more than just break blessings.
I was feeling pretty confident
we would win this battle,
but you guys are making me work for it.
Not good.
I've got to stop the captain, even if
it means I have to play the villain.
I don't really like the sound
of this, but you got it.
Hey! I'm up.
Wait, what the heck is going on?
I love me some fizzy,
but do you think you can try to be a bit
more gentle with the execution next time?
Hold up, what are you doing?
Come on, now.
Let's be reasonable.
Did you know they say when
someone is unconscious?
It's good practice to remove their shoes.
to ensure they don't get overheated?
Go heavy!
He already picked up on the
threat I'm trying to lay down.
I regret that I have no choice.
But I'm not unconscious, you know.
Are you serious?
I really hate being on this
side of a Boxxo battle.
Me too, bro.
The feeling is mutual.
Seriously, though.
I can't go all out with that brat around.
He does make this complicated.
It would be extremely hard
for anyone who isn't armed
with magic or special blessings
to fight in that dimension.
Oh, Captain.
I believe he's using Eye Breach
to cancel out the blizzard.
So that's it.
This must be the area of effect
for his Eye Breach power.
This fight is going nowhere fast.
What are you doing?
Stop goofing off and put out those flames.
Sorry, but I'm too far away.
You're completely useless.
We're in a dire situation.
He's moving close enough
to put out the fire.
And look, she's utterly
distracted at the moment.
This is our chance to
catch them off guard.
He's right.
We're pretty much doomed
if we don't act fast. Yes.
We need you to stay here, Boxo.
We can't risk taking Filmina
and the others along.
Hello there.
Try it.
She's gone.
I know I've seen this trick before.
It's just like when they ran away
in the scorching sand stratum.
Barrier! I preach.
Forgive me, Boxo.
Holy crap, Cap.
My vending senses are tingling like mad.
You're actually the one
we were after all along.
oh
Right.
Up.
Up. Up.
I'm waiting for you, I'm waiting for you?
I'm waiting for you to feel you.
Oh, it's a good idea!
I can't see you, I can't see you.
I can't see you.
I look forward to serving you again.